A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, United States International Affairs Program (USIAP), Program Related Investments, Office Files of Marianne D. Inghilterra FA1521
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, United States International Affairs Program (USIAP), Program Related Investments, Office Files of Marianne D. Inghilterra
1980-1987
Rockefeller Archive Center
Inghilterra, Marianne D.
Ford Foundation
FA1521
1 Cubic Feet 3 boxes (2 letter document containers and 1 half-letter document containers)
Scope and Contents
The collection contains Marianne D. Inghilterra's program related investments correspondence with grantees, primarily regarding compliance with Ford Foundation grant requirements, and invoices. The collection also includes reports related to program related investment strategies, specific grantees, and internal budgets.
Biographical / Historical
Marianne D. Inghilterra was a Program Related Investments and Grants Administrator at the Ford Foundation from 1971-2002.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2019 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as Accession 2019:025.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into two series:
1. Chronological Correspondence Files, 1984-1987
2. Reports, 1980-1987
- Chronological Correspondence Files, 1984-1987; 1
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Chronological Correspondence, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6-8)
- Reports, 1980-1987; 2
  - Trinkhaus Reports, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Scope and Contents
    Reports on:
    Citizens' Coal Company
    Black Gentlemen Communications Company
    Support Services Alliance, Inc - Inquiry - August 1980 - "Program Related Investment" Loan Application
    Southern Agriculture Corporation/Southern Agriculture Swine Corporation
  - Monthly Budget Versus Actual Reports, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Talks and Presentations, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    PRI Orientation
    November 7, 1986 Program Review
  - Financial Intermediary Modifications, 1987 April (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Grantmaking Seminar, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Program Related Investments Portfolio Monitoring, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - An Assessment of Program Related Investments Use of Loan Guarantees (2 folders), 1982 September (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - An Assessment of Program Related Investments Use of Social Financial Intermediaries, 1981 August (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Memos and Reports, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Robert F. McKeon memo
    Note from Margaret B. Lowe
    Orientation Meetings on the Technical Assistance Guide: Opportunities Under Federal Assistance Programs and Other Sources of External Financing For Minority Business Enterprises and How to Effectively Use Them
    Field Survey on the Distribution of Technical Assistance Guide: How to Effectively Sell to the Federal Government - A Practical Approach for Minority Small Business
    Proposal to Develop Two Technical Assistance Guides for Program Related Investments User Groups
    Proposal Request for Developing Two Technical Assistance Guides
    Proposed Budget: Export Sales Guide for Small Business
  - Articles of Interest and Recent Reports, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Social Investing Through Program Related Investments: A Report to the Ford Foundation, 1984 January-May (Box 3, Folder 19)